<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PhD Application | Duc Q. Nguyen</title><link>https://martinakaduc.github.io/tag/phd-application/</link><atom:link href="https://martinakaduc.github.io/tag/phd-application/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>PhD Application</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://martinakaduc.github.io/media/icon_hu263ca39e98b046b5641ca652ce5a1514_340372_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>PhD Application</title><link>https://martinakaduc.github.io/tag/phd-application/</link></image><item><title>The Prolonged Uncertainty of the PhD Application Period: Hope and Resilience</title><link>https://martinakaduc.github.io/post/phd-application/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinakaduc.github.io/post/phd-application/</guid><description>&lt;p>The process of applying for a PhD program, particularly at toptier institutions like MIT or Stanford, often evokes a complex mix of anticipation, self-doubt, and prolonged waiting. For many applicants, this period is a time of hopelessness and dejection, as the outcome remains uncertain until the final decision is revealed. This experience is especially poignant for those who perceive themselves as &amp;ldquo;ordinary&amp;rdquo; candidates—individuals without a litany of prestigious achievements, medals, or top-tier standardized test scores. Yet, the question persists: Is there a viable path for such candidates to secure admission, or does their chance resemble a statistical anomaly, akin to the rare occurrence of a black swan?&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="the-perception-of-prestige-and-the-ordinary-applicant">The Perception of Prestige and the &amp;ldquo;Ordinary&amp;rdquo; Applicant&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In current academia, admission to elite institutions is frequently associated with a well-documented profile of excellence. Successful applicants to Stanford, for instance, often boast an impressive array of accolades—research publications, international awards, and near-perfect academic records. This creates an imposing standard that can intimidate applicants whose strengths lie elsewhere. For a candidate with distinguished but unconventional experience—perhaps years of independent research, unique professional contributions, or resilience in overcoming personal challenges—the prospect of standing out amidst such competition may feel daunting. The probability of acceptance for such an individual might appear small, leading to the judgment that it constitutes a black swan event: an improbable outcome that defies expectation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nonetheless, this perspective overlooks a critical reality of admissions processes. While excellent achievements undoubtedly enhance a candidate&amp;rsquo;s profile, many programs, including those at top-tier universities, value diversity of thought, experience, and potential. A &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; applicant with a compelling narrative and demonstrated capacity for intellectual growth is not inherently excluded. The likelihood of success may be smaller than for those with traditional markers of excellence, but it is not negligible. Admissions committees are the treasure hunters trying their best to recognize the merit in candidates whose journeys deviate from the conventional path.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="slow-blooming-a-testament-to-persistence">Slow Blooming: A Testament to Persistence&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Slow blooming does not mean no blooming&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This adage offers a poignant reminder during this difficult waiting period. Academic and personal development do not adhere to a universal timeline. For some, brilliance manifests early, reflected in a cascade of awards and recognition. For others, it emerges gradually, shaped by persistence, endeavor, and unconventional experiences. The PhD application process, though often framed as a meritocratic sprint, also rewards those who have cultivated their potential over time. A candidate who lacks a glittering resume but demonstrates depth, resilience, and a clear vision for their research may still secure a slot among other excellences. The key lies in articulating this journey effectively, transforming their &amp;ldquo;seeming&amp;rdquo; ordinariness into a narrative of distinction.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="schrödingers-cat-and-the-phd-application-waiting-game">Schrödinger’s Cat and the PhD-Application Waiting Game&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The interim from submitting a PhD application to receiving a decision bears a striking resemblance to the thought experiment of Schrödinger’s cat. In quantum mechanics, the cat exists in a superposition—simultaneously alive and dead—until the box is opened and its state observed. Similarly, during the &amp;ldquo;dead&amp;rdquo; waiting period, an applicant occupies a liminal space, suspended between acceptance and rejection. The outcome is unknowable until the notification email is opened in the form of an admissions letter. This uncertainty can be profoundly disorienting, amplifying feelings of dejection as weeks stretch into months. Each passing day without news reinforces the sense of being trapped in a state of limbo, where hope and despair coexist in equal measure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet, just as Schrödinger’s paradox serves to illustrate the nature of observation, the PhD application waiting period underscores the importance of resilience. The applicant cannot alter the decision retroactively, but they can control their response to the uncertainty—maintaining focus on their goals, refining their research interests, and preparing for multiple outcomes. This mindset transforms the waiting period from a passive ordeal into an active phase of growth. By embracing the unknown, the applicant cultivates the resilience needed to navigate the academic landscape, regardless of the final decision.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="embracing-the-unknown">Embracing the Unknown&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The PhD application process, with its prolonged delays and multiple factors affecting it, tests the resolve of even the most determined candidates. For those without a traditional portfolio of achievements, the journey may feel particularly hopeless, the odds of success seemingly infinitesimal. However, the possibility of admission, though rare, is not illusory. Like a slow-blooming flower or the resolution of Schrödinger’s paradox, the outcome hinges on factors beyond immediate control—yet it remains within the realm of possibility. To navigate this period, we — applicants, must balance realistic expectations with unwavering perseverance, recognizing our unique experiences, however understated, hold intrinsic value. In the end, the dejected waiting will give you not only an answer but also a deeper understanding of your own capacity for endurance and hope.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your effort will pay off, and the waiting will end. The cat will be alive, and the box will be open.
Please believe in yourself and keep the hope alive. Don&amp;rsquo;t give up. You are extraordinary in your own way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>P/S: If you haven&amp;rsquo;t had any offers yet (like me this year), please remember that &amp;ldquo;slow blooming does not mean no blooming.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Duc Q. Nguyen&lt;br>
March 27, 2025&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Update: May 16, 2025&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;br>
I am happy to announce that I have received an offer from National University of Singapore for the PhD program in Computer Science. I am grateful for the support and encouragement from my friends, family, and mentors throughout this journey. Thank you all for believing in me and helping me to keep the hope alive. I am excited to embark on this new chapter of my academic career and look forward to contributing to the field of AI and NLP.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item></channel></rss>