<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects | Duc Q. Nguyen</title><link>https://martinakaduc.github.io/project/</link><atom:link href="https://martinakaduc.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Projects</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://martinakaduc.github.io/media/icon_hu263ca39e98b046b5641ca652ce5a1514_340372_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Projects</title><link>https://martinakaduc.github.io/project/</link></image><item><title>Large Language Models and Applications</title><link>https://martinakaduc.github.io/project/large_language_models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinakaduc.github.io/project/large_language_models/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, large language models have achieved state-of-the-art results on many natural language processing tasks. It is believed that large language models can learn the knowledge of the world from the text data. As the era of AGI (Artificial General Intelligence) is coming, large language models are considered as one of the key technologies to achieve AGI. In this project, I am interested in developing new large language models and applying them to solve real-world problems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Solving Graph Theory Problems</title><link>https://martinakaduc.github.io/project/graph_theory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinakaduc.github.io/project/graph_theory/</guid><description>&lt;p>Graph theory is a branch of mathematics that studies graphs, which are mathematical structures used to model pairwise relations between objects. A graph in this context is made up of vertices (also called nodes or points) which are connected by edges (also called links or lines). A graph can be directed or undirected, weighted or unweighted. Graphs are one of the prime objects of study in discrete mathematics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Problems in graph theory include graph or subgraph isomorphism, finding the largest clique in a graph, finding the chromatic number of a graph, finding the shortest path between two vertices, finding the minimum spanning tree of a graph, finding the maximum flow in a graph, etc. Currently, existing classical algorithms can solve these problems effectively. However, these algorithms are not scalable and cannot be applied to large-scaled graphs. In this project, I will explore how to use Deep Learning to solve graph theory problems with targeted large-scaled graphs and applications in drug discovery, social network analysis, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="masters-thesis">Master&amp;rsquo;s Thesis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis focuses on enhancing subgraph isomorphism prediction models to improve scalability and interpretability, particularly for applications in drug design. I introduce xNeuSM, an Explainable Neural Subgraph Matching framework, which leverages Graph Learnable Multi-hop Attention Networks (GLeMA) to dynamically learn attention decay parameters across multiple hops. This approach eliminates reliance on fixed hyperparameters and provides theoretical guarantees on approximation errors. Empirical results on real-world datasets show that xNeuSM has higher accuracy than approximate baselines while achieving query times at least seven times faster than exact algorithms. These advancements make subgraph matching more practical for large-scale molecular analysis in drug discovery.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis PDF: &lt;a href="https://martinakaduc.github.io/uploads/LVThS_2270664_NguyenQuangDuc.pdf">Link&lt;/a>&lt;br>
Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis presentation: &lt;a href="https://martinakaduc.github.io/slides/Slide_2270664_NguyenQuangDuc.pdf">Link&lt;/a>&lt;br>
Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis code: &lt;a href="https://github.com/martinakaduc/xNeuSM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Link&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="publications">Publications&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Duc Q. Nguyen, &lt;em>et al.&lt;/em> &amp;ldquo;10X Faster Subgraph Matching: Dual Matching Networks with Interleaved Diffusion Attention&amp;rdquo;, In &lt;em>Proceedings of 2023 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks&lt;/em> (IJCNN), 2023. &lt;a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10191159" target="_blank" rel="noopener">[PDF]&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://github.com/martinakaduc/xDualSM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">[Code]&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Duc Q. Nguyen, &lt;em>et al.&lt;/em>, &amp;ldquo;Explainable Neural Subgraph Matching With Learnable Multi-Hop Attention,&amp;rdquo; &lt;em>IEEE Access&lt;/em>, vol. 12, pp. 130474–130492, 2024. &lt;a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10677500" target="_blank" rel="noopener">[PDF]&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://github.com/martinakaduc/xNeuSM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">[Code]&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Drug Discovery</title><link>https://martinakaduc.github.io/project/drug_discovery/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinakaduc.github.io/project/drug_discovery/</guid><description>&lt;p>Drug discovery is a complex, expensive, and time-consuming process. It involves the identification of a target, screening of a large number of molecules, and optimization of the selected molecules. The process of drug discovery can be accelerated by using machine learning and deep learning. I am interested in solving problems in drug discovery using deep learning. I am also interested in developing new deep learning models for drug discovery.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="graduate-thesis">Graduate Thesis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My graduate thesis was on the application of deep learning to drug discovery. I worked on the the problem of building pharmacophore model for a given molecule (COVID-19 Mpro). The pharmacophore model of a molecule is a set of points in 3D space that represent the important features of the molecule. The pharmacophore model is used to screen a large number of molecules to find the molecules that are promising candidates for drug discovery. I used a deep learning model to build the pharmacophore model of a molecule. My approach contains following steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Using a deep learning model to predict the binding affinity of a molecule to a target protein (Mpro).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using the predicted binding affinity to find the binding site of the molecule on the target protein.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using the binding site to build the pharmacophore model of the molecule.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using the pharmacophore model to screen a large number of molecules to find the molecules that are promising candidates for drug discovery and build a recommender system for drug discovery.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>My built system is available at &lt;a href="http://www.ura.hcmut.edu.vn/vidok/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Link&lt;/a>.&lt;br>
Account: Test&lt;br>
Password: test&lt;br>
Or you can register a new account.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thesis PDF: &lt;a href="https://martinakaduc.github.io/uploads/HK212_6_LVTN_Finish_NguyenQuangDuc_1810118_Nop.pdf">Link&lt;/a>&lt;br>
Thesis presentation: &lt;a href="https://martinakaduc.github.io/slides/Thesis_Presentation.pdf">Link&lt;/a>&lt;br>
Thesis code: &lt;a href="https://github.com/ViDok-BK" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Link&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="publications">Publications&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Duc Q. Nguyen, et al. &amp;ldquo;Towards de Novo Drug Design for the Coronavirus: A Drug-Target Interaction Prediction Approach Using Atom-Enhanced Graph Neural Network with Multi-Hop Gating Mechanism&amp;rdquo; In &lt;em>Proceedings of 2022 9th Nafosted Conference on Information and Computer Science&lt;/em> (2022). &lt;strong>Best Paper Award&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10013437" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Link&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>